<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programmer Journey</title>
    <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Programmer Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 10:41:41 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.programmerjourney.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooltip on a Highcharts Legend</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/highcharts-legend-tooltip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 10:41:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/highcharts-legend-tooltip/</guid>
      <description>Looking for a way to add tooltips to the legends of your Highcharts charts? Let me show you how to do it.
Requirement At my current project we use a lot of initials and abbreviations and we decided that a tooltip on a legend would be the most effective way to show a quick explanation to the user.
Solution To create the tooltip we just need to change the chart&amp;rsquo;s options to enable the useHTML property to render the legend and add the tooltip logic to the labelFormatter property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# List of Tuples with Named Fields</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/csharp-list-tuples-named-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 07:23:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/csharp-list-tuples-named-fields/</guid>
      <description>One of these days I was developing a project using tuples with named fields, making it easier to understand the code when using tuples. I then wanted to create a List of them but the way to do it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be straightforward to me. So I decided to show you all the use cases of tuples in this post.
Unnamed fields tuple This is the most simple case of tuples when you don&amp;rsquo;t specify a name to the fields and they are named by Item1, Item2, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing parent component to refresh when using a State container in Blazor</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/blazor-forcing-parent-refresh-state-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 17:00:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/blazor-forcing-parent-refresh-state-container/</guid>
      <description>One of the ways that I use to communicate between Blazor components in large applications is to use a state container. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can force the parent container to refresh when needed. You can find the source code for this here.
In this example, we have a page with two components where each component has a button and also an alert showing the selected component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate Blazor into Razor Pages</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/integrate-blazor-into-razor-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 14:34:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/integrate-blazor-into-razor-pages/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at Blazor components for some time and I was looking for a way to integrate them into my existing ASP.NET Core 3.1 Web applications. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy!
Setup In the layout file _Layout.cshtml add this &amp;lt;base&amp;gt; tag to the &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; element:
&amp;lt;base href=&amp;#34;~/&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; Also in the layout file _Layout.cshtml add this &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; tag before the closing &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; tag:
&amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;_framework/blazor.server.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; Add an _Imports.razor Blazor component to your Pages folder:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a button to Highcharts</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/highcharts-add-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 12:10:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/highcharts-add-button/</guid>
      <description>Do you know that you can add buttons to your Highcharts graphs? In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how.
Requirement At my current project I have a requirement to add a button to a bar graph with a Font Awesome icon. In this example my button will show an Hello World alert so you can easily change it for your needs.
Solution To create the button I used the SVGRenderer that allows to create SVG drawings on your charts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highcharts Draggable Bar color validation</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/highcharts-paint-bar-drag/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 11:22:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/highcharts-paint-bar-drag/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can create visual rules for your Highcharts when the user is dragging points or bars.
Requirement At my current project I have a requirement to visually show the user that their input is invalid. In this case the bar should be red instead of blue. The validation is that at least one of the values should be at the maximum value (10 in my case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highcharts Draggable Bar workaround</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/highcharts-draggable-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:22:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/highcharts-draggable-bar/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing charts with Highcharts for around 1 year now. It is a great charting engine and very easy to use so I highly recommend it!
draggable-points Module One of the modules that I use in some of my graphs is the draggable-points. This module allows to drag and drop points around the graph allowing the user to have a visual input. That small circle at the end of the bar is a visual guidance telling the user that the bar is draggable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding comments to a Hugo blog with Disqus</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/hugo-add-disqus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 11:29:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/hugo-add-disqus/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to add comments to a Hugo blog with Disqus.
Signup to Disqus The first step is to create an account on Disqus and add your site to the account. The basic plan is free to use.
Add Disqus Short Name Then we need to add the Disqus Short Name to your blog config.toml
disqusShortname = &amp;#34;yourshortname&amp;#34; Done! It&amp;rsquo;s very easy!
For more details read the official documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editing Razor views when debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/razor-views-debug-edit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 10:18:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/razor-views-debug-edit/</guid>
      <description>If you have been programming with Razor Pages on ASP.NET Core 3.0 you know that restarting your application every time you make a change is not very productive.
By default, your changes are not refreshed automatically and you need to restart your application. Let me show you how to change this behavior.
Add required Nuget package You need to add the Microsoft.AspNetCore.Mvc.Razor.RuntimeCompilation Nuget to your project.
Edit project file This Nuget should be only referenced when you are running your application in Debug mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a programmer&#39;s blog</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/starting-a-programmers-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 22:53:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/starting-a-programmers-blog/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about starting my programmer&amp;rsquo;s blog for 3 years now and I finally decided to go for it.
Here are the reasons why I have started it and why you should do it too!
Do programmers need a blog? Yes! A programming blog is a portfolio for programmers.
If you were a designer, an artist or a model you would have for sure a portfolio where you could show your work to the world, your accomplishments, what you are really capable of doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Pedro and I&amp;rsquo;m based in Portugal where I work remotely from my home office.
I&amp;rsquo;m an experienced software developer &amp;amp; team leader and in this blog I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing my notes on everything I learn in my journey as a programmer. I hope that they are also helpful for you.
I&amp;rsquo;ve started my programming career with PL/SQL and Oracle database. Some years later I moved to the .NET stack (C# and Razor) and I also develop some projects with Javascript front-end frameworks such as Angular and React.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a simple free blog</title>
      <link>https://www.programmerjourney.com/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.programmerjourney.com/hugo/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll guide you in how to create a simple blog site using Hugo as a static site generator and Github Pages to host it. This solution is free but I suggest that you buy your own domain which is around $10/year!
Install Hugo The instructions to install Hugo are different for each operation system so please read the official documentation.
After installation is complete run hugo new site MyBlog:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>